Atul Kumar Singh

Software Developer

② Lucknow, UP, IN **№** <u>+91 7518299883</u>

Profiles

in linkedin.com/in/atulsingh369

github.com/atulsingh369

* linktr.ee/atulsingh369

Skills

Languages

C / C++, Java, Python, JavaScript (JS), TypeScript (TS), HTML/CSS, Go

Frameworks

Angular, React, Next.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Ionic, Nest.js, Flutter

Tools

Git / GitHub, Firebase, AWS, Tailwind CSS, Cypress, Semantic UI, Material UI, Jira, Confluence, Notion, PostgreSQL, Canva, Figma, Project IDX, Slack

Concepts

RESTful APIs, Agile / Scrum, Data Structures & Algorithms, Cloud Computing, Load Balancing, Caching, DB Sharding, Microservices

Interests

Badminton

Chess

Practice Projects

- Task Scribe
- Ø Time Minder
- Para Genius

Awards

Novathon Winner GDSC-GFG BBDEC Chapter

Certifications

The Full Stack Meta

The Bits and Bytes of Computer Networking Google

References

Available upon Request

@ atulsingh.0369@gmail.com

Summary

Motivated Software Developer with 1.2+ year of experience in full-stack development, specializing in web technologies and agile methodologies, stacks such as MERN and MEAN, including AWS and Firebase incorporating tools like Git/GitHub, Jira, Confluence and Notion, and frameworks like Next.js, Nest.js and Ionic with Capacitor. Seeking on-site or remote opportunities to contribute to innovative projects while continuously expanding skills in software engineering.

Education

Dr. APJ Abdul Kalam Technical University Civil Engineering

June 2020 - June 2024 Bachelor of Technology

Experience

Shreeva Soft-Tech InnovationsFull Stack Developer

October 2023 - September 2024 Prayagraj, UP

A https://shreeva.in

- Developed an integrated ecosystem for company initiatives, resulting in a 120% productivity increase.
- Implemented Agile and Scrum methodologies, enhancing development efficiency by 80%.
- Utilized AngularJS, AWS, Go, and cross-platform frameworks like lonic with Capacitor
- Worked with MVC architecture and service model patterns.

Uttar Pradesh Housing & Development August Board

August 2023 - September 2023 Lucknow, UP

Database Engineer Intern & https://upavp.in

- Automated database performance optimization tasks, improving query response time by 35%.
- Enhanced data modeling techniques, increasing data security by 25%.
- Collaborated on high-performance applications for the Government of Uttar Pradesh.

Pixel Business

March 2022 - May 2022 Remote, IN

- Created responsive interfaces, reducing page reload time by 40%.
- Improved user satisfaction rates from 42% to 67% through enhanced UX design.
- Developed cross-platform compatible UIs using React.js, HTML, CSS, and SCSS.

Projects

JobNexus

September 2024

August 2023

Visit here...Developed a Next.js-based job aggrega

- Developed a Next.js-based job aggregator app, integrating multiple job board APIs and reducing manual search time by 70%, with tracking response rates.
- Implemented Google Sheets API and Gmail API integration, automating the storage and mailing of over 100 job listings per week
- Engineered a responsive UI with React, resulting in a efficient system.

Next.js, React.js, Google Sheets API, Gmail API, Nodemailer, API Development

RaagBeats

- Developed a web API to fetch data from Spotify, improving music streaming efficiency by 40%.
- Designed an intuitive UI/UX, increasing user engagement by 180%.
- Technologies: Vite, React, SCSS, Tailwind CSS, React Hooks, Redux.

Native API's, SCSS, Tailwind CSS, React Hooks, Redux, React JS